Guide to the Consumer Reports. Frances Warne papers, 1936-1985 and undated RL.11797
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports. Frances Warne papers
1936-1985 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports (Firm)
RL.11797
1.0 Linear Feet
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. Frances Warne was an author, consumer advocate and instructor in home economics and consumer education; co-founder of Consumers Union. The Consumer Reports Frances Warne papers include clippings, correspondence, book manuscripts and drafts, course notes and other printed materials. The bulk of the collection pertains to "Wise Buymanship", a home economics and consumer education manual produced for the YWCA. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: Book Files; Personal and Professional Files.
Biographical / Historical
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. Frances Warne was an author, consumer advocate and instructor in home economics and consumer education; co-founder of Consumers Union.
Frances Lee Corbett was born in West Virginia in 1898 and raised in the Washington, D.C. area. She obtained an A.B. from Cornell University and a M.S. degree from the University of Massachusetts, Amherst. She married Colston E. Warne in 1920 and the two formed part of the group that founded Consumers Union in 1936. Frances Warne served as an instructor in consumer economics, consumer education and home economics at the University of Massachusetts. She was author of "Wise Buymanship" a manual of consumer education produced by Consumers Union for the YWCA. Frances Warne died in Massachusetts in 1982.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Consumer Reports. Frances Warne papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2019.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Advertising Council records
J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office. Information Center records
J. Walter Thompson Company. Information Center vertical files
J. Walter Thompson Company. Public Relations records
J. Walter Thompson Company. Rena Bartos papers
Nicole Di Bona Peterson Collection of Advertising Cookbooks
Collection Overview
The Consumer Reports Frances Warne papers include clippings, correspondence, book manuscripts and drafts, course notes and other printed materials. The bulk of the collection pertains to "Wise Buymanship", a home economics and consumer education manual produced for the YWCA.
Women consumers -- United States; Consumers; consumer protection; Consumer advocacy; Home economics -- United States -- History; Warne, Frances Lee Corbett; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; YWCA of the U.S.A.
- Book Files, 1959-1961 and undated; 1
  - Abridged/partial version (binder), approximately 1961 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Wise Buymanship: A Consumers Union Discussion Manual Prepared for the National Board of the Young Women's Christian Association
  - Copy 1 (binder), approximately 1959; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Copy 2 (binder, library copy from Henry Harrap), 1961; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Drafts and notes, 1959-1961 and undated; 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Drafts and notes, 1959-1961 and undated; 4 folders (Box 2)
- Personal and Professional Files, 1936-1985 and undated; 2
  - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence--Barbara Newell (Warne's daughter), 1969-1985 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence--Payment dispute with Consumers Union over payment for Wise Buymanship, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Course materials, 1936-1954 and undated; 5 folders (Box 2)
    Includes assignments, notes, pamplets and clippings, paper topics, syllabi and other materials used for courses in consumer economics, consumer education and home economics
  - Course materials, 1936-1954 and undated (Box 3)
  - Estate settlement, 1982-1985 (Box 3)
    Includes correspondence and documents relating to Warne's will and probate